Hello, Gus.
Felicity.
Better make myself a date in here.
So, you on your way home?
I guess so.
You shouldn't get so overheated. You'll
catch pneumonia.
Ah.
Strong as a bull.
Yes.
I'm stuck here until I finish stacking
all this hair of wood.
I'll help.
Let's be with baby carrots.
Oh, gosh, I love you. Oh, I love you,
boy.
There you have it.
Complete. Finished.
I've brought you my manuscript to
critique in exchange for like services
as per our agreement.
Although, of course, I have no way to
rush the creative process of your own
unfinished work.
Lord, you do churn them out, don't you?
Perhaps we could, and I know it's short
notice.
Would you enjoy dining with me tomorrow
night?
Dining? Perhaps at the White Sands, at
my house with the children around. It's
not very intimate.
Intimate? No, it isn't.
Much easier to perform our editorial
task away from prying eyes.
Oh, Ted, I see.
Well, uh...
Privacy is a must amidst dangling
participles, to be sure.
Lucy, love God!
You're a bunch of trousers!
Lucy,
don't pay any attention to them.
Well, what was it like?
What was what like?
Did he embrace you in his arms first, or
did you have to kiss him?
How could you be so vulgar, Sarah?
Nothing happened.
How could anything happen?
I never get any privacy.
Not at school, not at home, not
anywhere.
You're so lucky living on your own with
Aunt Hedy. You can't be serious.
Living with five other people is like
living in a fishbowl.
At least you have your own room. No one
barges in on you. Aunt Hedy nearly makes
notes of anything that's moved from its
place in my room. It's not the same.
I'm sick of... Dean, you'll know soon
enough.
I want to be treated like a woman.
I want to know what it feels like to
swoon in a man's arms.
I thought you wanted to be kissed. I
mean, how can you swoon and kiss at the
same time?
Well, you... I don't know.
Sarah, what if I never find out?
What if I die an old maid in Avonlea
without ever having been kissed?
Or swooned.
And you too, Daniel. Look at the mess
you've made for Mummy. Oh, my God.
Look what your son's done.
Look at this mess.
Mess, this?
I got a brood of incontinent pigs.
That dog is possessed, I swear.
It's inspiring to make my life a misery.
We'll take the devil over nature any
day. One more foot of snow on that barn
roof, it'll collapse.
I have been lugging children and wet
laundry and pails around all day long.
arms are about to snap off. Well, you
don't need arms as much as you need a
back. And mine, oof. Well, sell it.
Don't be silly. Arms are way more
important than back.
Janet, a back is like a chin. It's what
defines a man. It's what makes us
different to jellyfish. I mean, arms.
Oh, well, arms are what?
Accessories, I suppose.
Well...
You're right, if I didn't have arms, I
couldn't do that.
What?
I mean, I couldn't take dancing.
Dancing?
Oh, Alec, we haven't had a real night
out since... I don't remember when.
Well, my beauty, what do you say?
We should be able to steal away for one
evening.
How romantic, Father.
Surely you could knock.
If you were to live up to your
intentions, Father, I'd be more than
babysit.
Without a care in the world, you and
Mother could stay out as late as you
to.
What a heavenly idea.
Father and father are going off to the
White Sands tomorrow night, and I'm
babysitting. Not me, you're not.
Exactly. If you make yourself scarce, I
won't tell if you won't.
Oh, Felicity, shame on you.
Do we have a bargain?
You could stay at our house. You could
stay in a rabbit hole for all I care.
Just don't be at home.
What's in it for me?
A night of freedom.
What's in it for you, Felicity? I know
you're up to something.
Oh, God.
Felicity, don't be so juvenile. And
don't be so stuck up and serious.
If you tell your father that you're at
my house and I tell my parents I'm at
your house... Then we can go anywhere
and do anything we want. We could go to
the lighthouse and maybe see the ghost
of the golden flea.
But what about Gus?
I'll bet Gus won't be there if Felicity
has anything to do with it.
Oh, no, I do hesitate to leave you on
your own now.
Aunt Hattie, I'm old enough to stay by
myself.
You are?
Well, all right.
Besides, with Janet and Alex so close
by, should you get lonely, you can
stay there, can't you?
Felicity, come in.
Hurry, don't let in the cold.
Hello, Aunt Hattie.
I'm so nervous.
Will you take care of Cecily and Daniel?
Of course, but you are taking a chance
inviting God.
Sarah, come with me.
Felicity, if you're too frightened to
even ask him to dinner, how are you
to eat with him?
I heard your voice and I thought I was
dreaming.
I was in the neighborhood.
I mean, um, do you like beef?
Well, it doesn't have to be beef,
really. Not everyone likes beef.
If you'd like to, would you like to come
to dinner tomorrow night?
Sure.
What time would your mother expect me?
My mother.
You're probably working, aren't you? No.
It's my night off.
Well, you might have other plans.
I never turned down a meal.
Oh.
God.
Fine.
Oh, wonderful.
Six o 'clock, then.
Six and a half.
I don't know what's possessed you for.
You're making eyes at me all day.
I said to you, really, Janet, don't go
putting nonsense in the girl's head.
Good night, Felix.
Yes, you behave yourself with the
pettibones, huh? Yes.
You must be imagining things, Father.
Mr. Pettibone doesn't let us get away
anything. It's worse than here.
Good. Good night.
Oh, yes, Felicity. When you give Daniel
his bottle, be sure and rub his back
afterwards because if he has any gas at
all, he won't sleep.
Oh, and don't, for heaven's sakes,
jiggle him. I won't.
And make sure he's in bed no later than
7 .30. Yes, Mother.
And don't let him suck his thumb.
Oh, and... Good night.
Cecily, they're gone. Hurry.
Hurry.
All right, I'm going. But remember, you
promised to help me with my mathematics
for two months. Yes.
I promise I promise I promise
I can't decide.
Will this do?
And how do you look absolutely
resplendent?
Now, Sarah, you mustn't be excessive.
After all, it is only a... A business
dinner.
Oh, yes, quite.
What?
Aunt Hattie, you wouldn't mind if Bethel
and Daniel stayed to keep me company,
would you?
Oh, what a good idea.
Where's Melissa Day? Oh, Lord.
Well, I hope there's enough supper for
everyone.
I don't know.
Great Josephette.
Calm yourself, children.
Calm yourself.
Just a minute.
Uh -oh.
Forgot my manners.
Wouldn't want your father hearing me
doing something so disrespectful.
My father isn't home.
Oh.
Sure is quiet around here.
Jeff, you and... Me.
Everyone else had an urgent plan that
came up at the last minute.
I couldn't bear to inconvenience you
guys.
You know, I think that you are more
radiant now than the day I married you.
Well, Alec, maybe that's because I'm
married to a man like you.
Who gave you four wild children.
Oh, but they're very good -looking
children, Alec. I mean, they could have
wild and...
Hideously ugly. No.
Not with a mother like you.
Would you like some more beef?
Uh, yeah.
Please.
Uh, you had to know it was my favorite.
Better than Chef Pierre can cook up over
at the White Sun.
How thoughtful of you.
The potatoes. Uh, yes, please.
The carrots.
Not to mention that you look a darn
sight prettier in an apron.
Oh, they're my favorite vegetable.
Also my favorite, yeah.
And parsnips.
Uh, did I tell you how much I like your
hair up?
Alec, I'd never agree to that, and you
know it.
So you see, it turns the plot 360
degrees.
Oh, that's positively ingenious.
A romantic liaison with a handsome
neighbor.
Ah, interesting.
Oh, Alec.
Alec, the positive.
Improper. That's what I call it.
Improper.
Inelegant. And inequivocably flat.
Oh, without adjectives, it's like...
Janet,
Alec, are you out? For criticism.
Good evening.
You certainly know how to dish it out
quite very well.
But can you take it? That's what I want
to know. I'm sorry, but will we stop
acting like children?
Children?
Children.
You're watching mine.
Teddy, I'm sorry.
It was only meant as constructive
criticism. Surely you can see there are
many adjectives. Teddy, please.
One night out after something like two
years ruined.
It's not like Felicity let the children
get away with murder.
She's usually so on top of everything.
Father, you won't believe what we heard.
For your sake, Izzy.
I hope I do.
Nate,
hot bear.
More wood still?
No, no.
That's all right.
Coffee's cooling down, huh?
Oh, but this is your best shirt.
It's fine.
Really. Well, don't you need it for work
tomorrow?
Uh -huh.
Coffee stains if you don't get it out
quickly.
All right, what's going on?
You're home.
Mr. King, sir.
Gus Pike.
I want to know just what business it is
of yours to be here with Felicity
unbeknownst to us.
I asked him, Father.
Felicity, how could you be so
irresponsible to ship our babies off
night?
Mr. King, it's not what it... You'd
better get out of that house.
Now.
And that's for you, young lady.
I never get to be alone.
Oh, Felicity, that's not the point.
We trusted you.
We brought you up to be responsible.
I told you, nothing happened.
Have respect.
For us, for yourself, for the moral code
of this community.
Why can't you believe me?
Believe what?
The lie about your babysitting the
children?
Or the lie you had your brother tell us?
Or the lie... Alec. You had the
Pettibone children tell us? Or the lie
you had Sarah tell?
Alec.
Everything you have done tonight has
been a lie. Now, why should I believe
now?
We didn't do anything.
We just wanted to spend some time
together.
We just wanted to be together. Is that
so terrible?
Well, your freedom is a thing of the
past, young lady. If I catch you so much
speaking with Gus Pike, even thinking
about him, I'll... Doesn't anybody
understand?
It's awful.
How could I be such a fool?
I've got to apologize to Gus, but I'm
not permitted to see him or even speak
him.
He may never want to speak to me again.
They're the lowest moment of my entire
life.
You'll have to write Gus a letter.
But it'll be so feeble.
I mean, what do I say?
Dear Gus, I'm so sorry I lied to you
too.
He'll laugh at it anyway.
Not if it's heartfelt.
Dearest Gus.
Well, well, well. A secret message,
perhaps?
Is there any reason we all can't be
privy to it, Miss Stanley?
It's nothing, sir, really.
Let us be the judge of that.
Would you please read it to the class?
My dearest Gus.
My heart is breaking at the thought of
never speaking to you again.
I quiver at the thought of your hand
touching mine.
I apologize from the very depths of my
soul.
I must speak with you through an
intermediary.
Intermediary, indeed.
Who, I wonder?
Please go on.
Mr. Pettibone, sir.
Please forgive my reckless adventure.
Reckless is misspelled.
Perhaps, Miss Stanley, you will do me
the honor of staying after school. You
will write an essay on how reckless
ventures most often end in disaster.
Yes, sir.
Isn't that right, Miss King?
First comes love, then comes marriage,
then comes... Push it.
Straight home.
Miss Stanley?
Have you got a good start on your
assignment?
Yes, sir.
Then you may go.
Since you're so adept at delivering
letters, perhaps you could deliver this
to your aunt.
It's about my reprimand.
Please, sir.
Please, just give it to your aunt.
I don't care what they say.
They can't keep us apart. Quiver at the
thought. How romantic.
Well, I suppose that... I respect your
father,
Felicity.
But he don't respect me.
And I ain't coming around to King Farm
till I change it.
But, Gus, I... That's just the way I
feel.
You're afraid of my father, aren't you?
No, Felicity, I'm not.
But I'm not so foolish as you've been,
making up all them stories.
You're a coward.
afraid of is ruining my chances with
you.
We have to lay low now.
That's what your father said, and that's
what we have to do.
You're right to be afraid.
If my father doesn't shoo you away, I
will.
I think, Sarah, Mr.
King was looking for an excuse to
separate me and Felicity.
He doesn't think I'm good enough for
her, and I'm not.
I mean, I don't know why she acted like
she liked me in the first place.
Gus, she worships the ground you walk
on.
Really?
You're just saying that.
I like you, Gus.
Why shouldn't she?
You know, I had my cop set for Felicity
a long time ago.
Somehow I got to set things right.
I know you will, God.
See you later.
What if I were to add a tragic romance?
Say, with a handsome neighbor who
happens into her life, then you see
torn between reason and passion. Oh,
yes!
Oh,
that's a great idea!
Oh, hello, Sarah.
Are you delivering the post now?
Ah, yes.
Aunt Petty?
It all started out quite innocently.
I want you to understand that it was all
for Felicity's sake.
Mr. Pettybone asked me to give this to
you.
Don't judge me too harshly.
Don't worry, Sarah.
Hardly consider Mr. Pitybone the best
arbiter of good conduct.
Note on your conduct, Sarah?
My dear Miss King.
Oh, Hattie, this isn't about Sarah at
all.
What the riddle? Listen to this.
As a bee longs for honey, so do I long
for your forgiveness.
That's sweet.
I suffer interminably, no comma.
I await your reply.
Well, suffer on, Mr. Pettibone.
The poor man is trying desperately to
apologize.
He's neither poor, Olivia, nor is he
much of a man, as far as I can discern.
I don't think I'm wrong on that, Janet.
I mean, Gus Pike has always seemed like
a decent young fellow, but it takes two
to dance. I've come to the conclusion
that they're both at fault.
Well, Alec, they're in love.
When you're in love, you do silly
things. She is too young to be in love.
not prepared.
You're not prepared?
Huh? To let your daughter grow up.
No, I...
You can't protect your little girl
forever.
I mean, we've got to let her make
mistakes, or else she'll never learn
Look, if she's old enough to be inviting
boys for dinner and gallivanting
around, then I'm... Well, you're not
ready to be put out to pasture yet, if
that's what you're worried about.
I don't know.
I've been thinking.
You're right.
I was too harsh, Sarah.
Maybe you should talk to Felicity.
Put my foot in it again?
Sarah, could you... Would you write one
of those letters yours to
Felicity for me?
Not you too.
Can't stand her being angry.
Please? All right.
Let's see.
Uncle Alec and Aunt Janet usually go to
bed quite early.
A love letter delivered under the cover
of darkness.
Doc! I have something for you.
I'll come down.
No.
I have a letter.
Begging your pardon, sir, but you
misread what happened last night.
Look, you may be able to put something
over on my daughter. She's young and
innocent, but you can't do it to me.
Whoa there, Mr. King.
I do like your daughter, but I assure
you I have only the best intentions.
Oh, I know all about your intentions. I
was young once myself.
Sir, can't we step inside and sort this
out reasonably?
Father. To let you into my house with my
daughter, you must think I'm a bloody
fool. Father, don't hurt him.
Look, you get back into the house right
now and cover yourself up, girl.
And you, you better get off my property
right now before I do something I may
regret.
Yes, sir.
Gus!
I hate you!
You humiliated me to the bone!
I'm disowning myself and this entire
family forever.
I tell you, Sarah, we made a mess of it.
Why?
Well, there's Sarah, you see, so you're
acting as good between us, managed to
complicate matters even further.
Let this be a lesson to you. I suppose
this means I won't be running any more
letters back and forth between you and
Mr. Pettibone?
Oh, sh... Sarah Stanley, such impudence.
Could everybody just stop fighting?
Please.
What I'll do, respect, Miss King.
I never knew till now how hot -headed
your family could be.
Love seems to bring out the worst in all
of us.
Doesn't it, Miss Ken?
I'd almost rather not be in love. It
means I have to give up my good name.
I don't know which I'd choose.
Being able to share my heart with
someone or
being able to hold my head up high to my
neighbors.
Watch what you do with that gun.
Oh, you're wise for your years, you are,
Gunspike.
If I have my way, you won't have to
choose.
You look more upset than I thought.
Eddie, what can I do for you?
Alec, why in heaven's name are you being
so bullish with Gus?
Well, you don't have a 16 -year -old
daughter to worry about, do you?
Well, if you ask me, it's a clear case
of the pot calling the kettle black.
Now, what is that supposed to mean?
Just this.
As I recall, you once found yourself
in...
Much the same predicament with the
Reverend Ward, did you not?
Back then, when you were pursuing Janet
over Hill and Dale like some mad bull
terrier. Now, hold on. Janet pursued me.
We all know that Janet was flighty,
somewhat less than proper, perhaps,
There was nothing improper about Janet's
behavior.
Poor girl was just madly in love with
me.
Oh, well, then.
Why would you think any the less of your
daughter than you did of your wife?
You needn't worry about Gus, Pike.
He's a gentleman, through and through to
the very core of his being.
I'll stick my reputation on it.
Well, he's certainly more of a gentleman
than you ever were at that age.
Now, wait a minute.
I remember it well.
as Mr. Pettibone, but Jasper would
dearly love some male accompaniment and
hopefully somebody older than three
months.
In that case, I accept your dinner
invitation. Oh, good.
Here we are.
As luck would have it, my children will
be at the King's. I wasn't looking
forward to a lonely evening.
Oh, well, rest assured you won't be
lonely for a minute.
Well, see you tonight.
Oh, Olivia, what a surprise.
And how is our Montgomery today?
He's fine.
I did drop by to invite you to dinner
tonight, Hattie.
Jasper's away, and the baby's been
asking for you.
Oh, well, you don't speak yet, do you,
my boy?
So how could she possibly know that you
miss your favorite aunt?
Mother's intuition, I guess.
I can't stand this anymore.
I'm living in this fistful.
Every move I make is subject to mother
and father's scrutiny.
They pushed us away and made me look
like a jellyfish.
I'm running away, and you're going to
help me.
You mean you'll be very happy.
Thank you, Felix, for your trouble.
It's customary to give your valet a tip.
All right, Felix, here's a tip.
Don't brush your teeth with a brick.
to believe that you don't want me.
I lugged my thing all the way out here.
It's not that I don't want your
felicity.
You know how I feel about you.
It's just not right.
We have to respect your father's wishes.
My father's wishes?
What about our wishes?
I just want us to have some time to
ourselves.
To be able to be by ourselves.
Obviously, that's not what you want.
It is, Felicity.
I want everything you want.
You're amazing, you know that?
Cooked up that harebrained dinner
scheme.
Defied your parents.
Lied to half of Avonlea.
Ran away from home.
All so you could be alone with me.
Now we're alone.
I'm about to throw you out.
Olivia?
Jasper?
It seems we're the only ones here,
madam.
Olivia?
It's a ruse.
How could she? A trap set by my very own
sister. Now, don't go flying off the
handle again, Hetty. Please, look me in
the eye.
I'm sorry I offended you.
Oh, you're sorry, are you?
I miss our talks.
Our friendship has broadened in scope
beyond mere literature.
Hetty, please.
If it makes you feel better, I re -read
my book.
And you were right. I got the plot all
wrong.
Oh, it's not all wrong.
It's one of your best -in -facts.
No, mine was all wrong.
Aunt Olivia, I
do want the truth.
When I fall in love...
Will all this trouble come my way?
Oh, Vera.
Nothing of real worth ever comes
completely without pain.
You know what, though?
You always remember the love more than
the pain.
Really? Mm -hmm.
You'll just have to take my word for it
for a little while, I guess.
Let's talk about this mind to mind.
When a man decides... No.
When she's grown up and she's old
enough... No.
Oui.
I got my own play.
I'm holding down two jobs and furthering
my schooling.
I read books at night, too.
Books about the world.
I honor value.
And I value honor more than most
everything else.
I... I'm coming to you with my head held
high and not like a thief in the night.
I... I
want to see your daughter, Felicity.
In the open.
And with your blessing.
Now, are you two going to come in for
some hot cider, or are you going to
out here and whisper in each other's
ear?
Hmm.
Thoughtless mutt.
Oh,
I suppose I have been overreacting all
along.
After all, we were once young and in
love.
What do you mean?
Tell me, when we were courting, was I
ever anything
but a gentleman?
Oh, no.
No, you were a perfect gentleman.
Thank you.
You drove me crazy.